Ronghua Xu, Ph.D.

☑ rxu22@binghamton.edu

https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=gKf0U28AAAAJ&hl=en

https://github.com/samuelxu999

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ronghua-xu-bu/



Biographical Sketch

About me

Ronghua Xu is an Tenure-Track Assistant Professor of Applied Computing at Michigan Technological University. He earned a Ph.D. and an M.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering at the Binghamton University - State University of New York (SUNY) in 2023 and 2018 respectively. He also received an M.S. in Mechanical and Electrical Engineering from Nanjing University of Aeronautics & Astronautics in 2010 and a B.S. in Mechanical Engineering from Nanjing University of Science & Technology, China in 2007. Before joining Binghamton University, he worked at Siemens on software development, system integration, and test automation from June 2010 to June 2016.

Research Interests

- ♦ Blockchain and Distributed Ledger Technology, Internet-of-Things (IoT), Machine Learning (ML), Cloud/Fog/Edge Computing Paradigm.
- ♦ Blockchain and smart contract enabled security solutions to Internet of Things (IoTs)
- ♦ Intelligence, assurance and resilience of next generation network.

Education

Dissertation title: A Secure-by-Design Federated Microchain Fabric for Internet-of-

Things(IoT) System
Advisor: Prof. Yu Chen

USA.

Thesis title: Capability Based Access Control Strategies to Deter DDoS Attacks Ex-

ploiting IoT Devices Advisor: Prof. Yu Chen

Sep 2007 – Mar 2010 \diamond MS, Mechanical and Electrical Engineering, Nanjing University of Aeronau-

tics & Astronautics, Nanjing, China.

Thesis title: Research on Form-to-function Mapping and Re-creative Design Method

Based on Function Ontology Advisor: Prof. Dunbing Tang

Employment History

August 2018 – August 2023 ♦ Graduate Researcher. Binghamton University-SUNY, NY, USA.

Employment History (continued)

June 2010 – June 2016

♦ **Software Engineer.** Department of Software Development, Research & Development Division, Siemens Numerical Control Ltd., Nanjing, China.

Teaching Experience

♦ Digital Forensics (SAT4816-5816), Fall 2023.

♦ Sophomore Design (EECE-287), Spring 2019, 2020.

♦ Computer Network Architecture (EECE-453/553), Fall 2018 - 2022.

♦ Network Security (EECE-658), Spring 2018 - 2019.

Skills

Languages \diamond Strong reading, writing and speaking competencies for English, Mandarin Chinese.

Coding \diamond C/C++, Java, Python, C#, VB, tclsh, bash, powershell, sql, xml/xsl, Lagrange Coding \diamond C/C++, Java, Python, C#, VB, tclsh, bash, powershell, sql, xml/xsl, Lagrange Coding \diamond C/C++, Java, Python, C#, VB, tclsh, bash, powershell, sql, xml/xsl, Lagrange Coding \diamond C/C++, Java, Python, C#, VB, tclsh, bash, powershell, sql, xml/xsl, Lagrange Coding \diamond C/C++, Java, Python, C#, VB, tclsh, bash, powershell, sql, xml/xsl, Lagrange Coding \diamond C/C++, Java, Python, C#, VB, tclsh, bash, powershell, sql, xml/xsl, Lagrange Coding \diamond C/C++, Java, Python, C#, VB, tclsh, bash, powershell, sql, xml/xsl, Lagrange Coding \diamond C/C++, Java, Python, C#, VB, tclsh, bash, powershell, sql, xml/xsl, Lagrange Coding Codin

Databases \diamond Mysql, Postgresql, sqlite.

Web Dev ♦ HTML, css, JavaScript, Flask Web Server.

Misc. \diamond Academic research, teaching, training, consultation.

Research Publications

Journal Articles

- Liu, X., Xu, R., & Chen, Y. (2024). A decentralized digital watermarking framework for secure and auditable video data in smart vehicular networks. *Future Internet*, 16(11), 390. Odoi:10.3390/fi16110390
- 2 Qu, Q., Hatami, M., Xu, R., Nagothu, D., Chen, Y., Li, X., ... Chen, G. (2024). The microverse: A task-oriented edge-scale metaverse. *Future Internet*, 16(2), 60. 60 doi:10.3390/fi16020060
- Xu, R., Nagothu, D., Chen, Y., Aved, A., Ardiles-Cruz, E., & Blasch, E. (2024). A secure interconnected autonomous system architecture for multi-domain iot ecosystems. *IEEE Communications Magazine*, 62(7), 52–57. 6 doi:10.1109/MCOM.001.2300354
- Nagothu, D., **Xu**, **R.**, Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Aved, A. (2022). Deterring deepfake attacks with an electrical network frequency fingerprints approach. *Future Internet*, 14(5), 125. Odoi:10.3390/fi14050125
- **Xu**, **R.**, & Chen, Y. (2022a). μ Dfl: A secure microchained decentralized federated learning fabric atop iot networks. *IEEE Transactions on Network and Service Management*. 6 doi:10.1109/TNSM.2022.3179892
- **Xu**, **R.**, Chen, Y., Chen, G., & Blasch, E. (2022). Sausa: Securing access, usage, and storage of 3d point cloud data by a blockchain-based authentication network. *Future Internet*, 14(12), 354. Odoi:10.3390/fi14120354
- Xu, R., Wei, S., Chen, Y., Chen, G., & Pham, K. (2022). Lightman: A lightweight microchained fabric for assurance-and resilience-oriented urban air mobility networks. *Drones*, *6*(12), 421. *Θ* doi:10.3390/drones6120421
- Qu, Q., Xu, R., Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Aved, A. (2021). Enable fair proof-of-work (pow) consensus for blockchains in iot by miner twins (mint). *Future Internet*, 13(11), 291. Odoi:10.3390/fi13110291

- Xu, R., Nagothu, D., & Chen, Y. (2021b). Econledger: A proof-of-enf consensus based lightweight distributed ledger for iovt networks. *Future Internet*, 13(10), 248. Odi:10.3390/fi13100248
- Xu, R., Nikouei, S. Y., Nagothu, D., Fitwi, A., & Chen, Y. (2020). Blendsps: A blockchain-enabled decentralized smart public safety system. *Smart Cities*, 3(3), 928–951. Odoi:10.3390/smartcities3030047
- Xu, R., Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Chen, G. (2019). Exploration of blockchain-enabled decentralized capability-based access control strategy for space situation awareness. *Optical Engineering*, 58(4), 041609.

 ✓ doi:10. 1117/1.0E.58.4.041609
- **Xu**, **R.**, Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Chen, G. (2018c). Blendcac: A smart contract enabled decentralized capability-based access control mechanism for the iot. *Computers*, 7(3), 39. **𝚱** doi:10.3390/computers7030039

Conference Proceedings

- Nagothu, D., **Xu**, **R.**, & Chen, Y. (2023). Dema: Decentralized electrical network frequency map for social media authentication. In *Disruptive technologies in information sciences vii* (Vol. 12542, pp. 57–72). SPIE.
- Nagothu, D., Xu, R., Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Ardiles-Cruz, E. (2023). Application of electrical network frequency as an entropy generator in distributed systems. In *Naecon 2023-ieee national aerospace and electronics conference* (pp. 233–238). IEEE.
- Ogunbunmi, S., Hatmai, M., **Xu**, **R.**, Chen, Y., Blasch, E., Ardiles-Cruz, E., ... Chen, G. (2023). A lightweight reputation system for uav networks. In *International conference on security and privacy in cyber-physical systems and smart vehicles* (pp. 114–129). Springer.
- Qu, Q., Xu, R., Sun, H., Chen, Y., Sarkar, S., & Ray, I. (2023). A digital healthcare service architecture for seniors safety monitoring in metaverse. In 2023 ieee international conference on metaverse computing, networking and applications (metacom) (pp. 86–93). IEEE.
- Wei, S., Huang, H., Chen, G., Blasch, E., Chen, Y., **Xu**, **R.**, & Pham, K. (2023). Rodad: Resilience oriented decentralized anomaly detection for urban air mobility networks. In 2023 integrated communication, navigation and surveillance conference (icns) (pp. 1–11). IEEE.
- **Xu**, **R.**, & Chen, Y. (2022b). Fairledger: A fair proof-of-sequential-work based lightweight distributed ledger for iot networks. In 2022 ieee international conference on blockchain (blockchain) (pp. 348–355). IEEE.
 Ø doi:10.1109/Blockchain55522.2022.00055
- Xu, R., Chen, Y., Li, X., & Blasch, E. (2022). A secure dynamic edge resource federation architecture for cross-domain iot systems. In 2022 international conference on computer communications and networks (icccn) (pp. 1–7). IEEE. Odi:10.1109/ICCCN54977.2022.9868843
- Nagothu, D., Xu, R., Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Aved, A. (2021a). Defake: Decentralized enf-consensus based deepfake detection in video conferencing. In 2021 ieee 23rd international workshop on multimedia signal processing (mmsp) (pp. 1–6). IEEE. doi:10.1109/MMSP53017.2021.9733503
- Nagothu, D., Xu, R., Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Aved, A. (2021b). Detecting compromised edge smart cameras using lightweight environmental fingerprint consensus. In *Proceedings of the 19th acm conference on embedded networked sensor systems* (pp. 505–510). ACM. doi:10.1145/3485730.3493684
- Xu, R., & Chen, Y. (2021). Fed-ddm: A federated ledgers based framework for hierarchical decentralized data marketplaces. In 2021 international conference on computer communications and networks (icccn) (pp. 1–8). IEEE. Odo::10.1109/ICCCN52240.2021.9522359
- Qu, Q., Xu, R., Nikouei, S. Y., & Chen, Y. (2020). An experimental study on microservices based edge computing platforms. In *Ieee infocom 2020-ieee conference on computer communications workshops (infocom wkshps)* (pp. 836–841). IEEE. doi:10.1109/INFOCOMWKSHPS50562.2020.9163068

- Xu, R., Chen, Y., Blasch, E., Aved, A., Chen, G., & Shen, D. (2020). Hybrid blockchain-enabled secure microservices fabric for decentralized multi-domain avionics systems. In *Sensors and systems for space applications xiii* (Vol. 11422, 114220J). International Society for Optics and Photonics. Odoi:10.1117/12. 2559036
- Xu, R., Chen, Y., & Li, J. (2020). Poster: Microfl: A lightweight, secure-by-design edge network fabric for decentralized iot systems. In *The network and distributed system security symposium (ndss)*. Retrieved from https://www.ndss-symposium.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/NDSS2020posters_paper_19.pdf
- Xu, R., Zhai, Z., Chen, Y., & Lum, J. K. (2020). Bit: A blockchain integrated time banking system for community exchange economy. In 2020 ieee international smart cities conference (isc2) (pp. 1–8). IEEE.
 doi:10.1109/ISC251055.2020.9239045
- Blasch, E., **Xu**, **R.**, Nikouei, S. Y., & Chen, Y. (2019). A study of lightweight dddas architecture for real-time public safety applications through hybrid simulation. In *2019 winter simulation conference* (wsc) (pp. 762–773). IEEE. 6 doi:10.1109/WSC40007.2019.9004727
- Nikouei, S. Y., **Xu**, **R.**, Chen, Y., Aved, A., & Blasch, E. (2019). Decentralized smart surveillance through microservices platform. In *Sensors and systems for space applications xii* (Vol. 11017, 110170K). International Society for Optics and Photonics. 6 doi:10.1117/12.2518999
- **Xu**, **R.**, Chen, S., Yang, L., Chen, Y., & Chen, G. (2019). Decentralized autonomous imaging data processing using blockchain. In *Multimodal biomedical imaging xiv* (Vol. 10871, pp. 72−82). SPIE. **⊘** doi:10.1117/12. 2513243
- Xu, R., Nikouei, S. Y., Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Aved, A. (2019). Blendmas: A blockchain-enabled decentralized microservices architecture for smart public safety. In 2019 ieee international conference on blockchain (blockchain) (pp. 564–571). IEEE. 6 doi:10.1109/Blockchain.2019.00082
- Xu, R., Ramachandran, G. S., Chen, Y., & Krishnamachari, B. (2019). Blendsm-ddm: Blockchain-enabled secure microservices for decentralized data marketplaces. In 2019 ieee international smart cities conference (isc2) (pp. 14–17). IEEE. odi:10.1109/ISC246665.2019.9071766
- Nagothu, D., **Xu**, **R.**, Nikouei, S. Y., & Chen, Y. (2018). A microservice-enabled architecture for smart surveillance using blockchain technology. In 2018 ieee international smart cities conference (isc2) (pp. 1–4). IEEE. Odo:10.1109/ISC2.2018.8656968
- Nikouei, S. Y., Chen, Y., Song, S., **Xu**, **R.**, Choi, B.-Y., & Faughnan, T. (2018). Smart surveillance as an edge network service: From harr-cascade, svm to a lightweight cnn. In 2018 ieee 4th international conference on collaboration and internet computing (cic) (pp. 256–265). IEEE. doi:10.1109/CIC.2018.00042
- Nikouei, S. Y., Chen, Y., Song, S., **Xu**, **R.**, Choi, B.-Y., & Faughnan, T. R. (2018). Real-time human detection as an edge service enabled by a lightweight cnn. In 2018 ieee international conference on edge computing (edge) (pp. 125–129). IEEE. doi:10.1109/EDGE.2018.00025
- Nikouei, S. Y., Xu, R., Nagothu, D., Chen, Y., Aved, A., & Blasch, E. (2018). Real-time index authentication for event-oriented surveillance video query using blockchain. In 2018 ieee international smart cities conference (isc2) (pp. 1–8). IEEE. 6 doi:10.1109/ISC2.2018.8656668
- Xu, R., Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Chen, G. (2018a). A federated capability-based access control mechanism for internet of things (iots). In *Sensors and systems for space applications xi* (Vol. 10641, 106410U). International Society for Optics and Photonics. 6 doi:10.1117/12.2305619
- Xu, R., Chen, Y., Blasch, E., & Chen, G. (2018b). Blendcac: A blockchain-enabled decentralized capability-based access control for iots. In 2018 ieee international conference on internet of things (ithings) and ieee green

- computing and communications (greencom) and ieee cyber, physical and social computing (cpscom) and ieee smart data (smartdata) (pp. 1027–1034). IEEE. 6 doi:10.1109/Cybermatics_2018.2018.00191
- Xu, R., Lin, X., Dong, Q., & Chen, Y. (2018). Constructing trustworthy and safe communities on a blockchainenabled social credits system. In *Proceedings of the 15th eai international conference on mobile and ubiquitous* systems: Computing, networking and services (pp. 449–453). 6 doi:10.1145/3286978.3287022
- Xu, R., Nikouei, S. Y., Chen, Y., Polunchenko, A., Song, S., Deng, C., & Faughnan, T. R. (2018). Real-time human objects tracking for smart surveillance at the edge. In 2018 ieee international conference on communications (icc) (pp. 1–6). IEEE. 60 doi:10.1109/ICC.2018.8422970

Book Chapters

- Xu, R., Nagothu, D., & Chen, Y. (2024). Ar-edge: Autonomous and resilient edge computing architecture for smart cities. (pp. 1–21). Odoi:10.5772/intechopen.1005876
- Xu, R., Nagothu, D., & Chen, Y. (2023). Ecom: Epoch randomness-based consensus committee configuration for iot blockchains. In *Principles and practice of blockchains* (pp. 135–154). Odoi:10.1007/978-3-031-10507-4_7
- **Xu**, **R.**, Chen, Y., & Blasch, E. (2021). Microchain: A light hierarchical consensus protocol for iot systems. In *Blockchain applications in iot ecosystem* (pp. 129–149). Springer.
- Nagothu, D., **Xu**, **R.**, Nikouei, S. Y., Zhao, X., & Chen, Y. (2020). Smart surveillance for public safety enabled by edge computing. In *Edge computing: Models, technologies and applications* (pp. 409–433). Odoi:10.1049/PBPC033E ch19
- **Xu**, **R.**, Chen, Y., & Blasch, E. (2020). Decentralized access control for iot based on blockchain and smart contract. In *Modeling and design of secure internet of things* (pp. 505–528). Odoi:10.1002/9781119593386. ch22
- Nikouei, S. Y., **Xu**, **R.**, & Chen, Y. (2019). Smart surveillance video stream processing at the edge for real-time human objects tracking. In *Fog and edge computing: Principles and paradigms* (pp. 319–346). Odoi:10.1002/9781119525080.ch13

Books

Xu, R., Chen, Y., & Blasch, E. (2023). Lightweight blockchain for internet of things: Rationale and a case study. Bellingham, Washington 98227-0010 USA: SPIE Press.

Professional Services

Conference Technical Program Committee (TPC)

- The 6th ACM International Workshop on BLockchain-enabled Networked Sensor Systems (BlockSys-24) (in conjunction with SenSys-20234.
- ♦ IEEE Fourth Intelligent Cybersecurity Conference (ICSC2024).
- ♦ IEEE/ACM International Conference on Connected Health: Applications, Systems and Engineering Technologies (CHASE 2024).
- ♦ The 2nd International Workshop on Decentralized Physical Infrastructure Network (DePIN 2024).
- ♦ The 29th IEEE Symposium on Computers and Communications (ISCC 2024).
- The 2024 EAI International Conference on Security and Privacy in Cyber-Physical Systems and Smart Vehicles (SmartSP 2024)
- ♦ The 7th IEEE International Conference on Blockchain (Blockchain-2024).
- ♦ The 6th IFIP International Internet of Things (IoT) Conference (IFIP-IoT 2023)

Professional Services (continued)

- ♦ The 5th ACM International Workshop on BLockchain-enabled Networked Sensor Systems (BlockSys-23) (in conjunction with SenSys-2023).
- The 2023 EAI International Conference on Security and Privacy in Cyber-Physical Systems and Smart Vehicles (SmartSP 2023)
- ♦ The 6th IEEE International Conference on Blockchain (Blockchain-2023).
- Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning Technologies for IoT (AMT) (IEEE WiMob-SPPDT'2023).
- ♦ The 6th International Workshop on BLockchain Enabled Sustainable Smart Cities (BLESS 2023) (in conjunction with ICCCN 2023 Conference).
- ♦ The 4th ACM International Workshop on BLockchain-enabled Networked Sensor Systems (BlockSys-22) (in conjunction with SenSys-2022).
- ♦ The 5th IEEE International Conference on Blockchain (Blockchain-2022).
- ♦ The 5th International Workshop on BLockchain Enabled Sustainable Smart Cities (BLESS 2022) (in conjunction with ICCCN 2022 Conference).
- ♦ WiMob Short Papers, Posters and Demos Track (IEEE WiMob-SPPDT'2022).
- ♦ The 4th IEEE International Conference on Blockchain (Blockchain-2021).
- The 4th International Workshop on BLockchain Enabled Sustainable Smart Cities (BLESS 2021) (in conjunction with ICCCN 2021 Conference).
- ♦ The 3rd IEEE International Conference on Blockchain (Blockchain-2020).
- ♦ The 3rd International Workshop on BLockchain Enabled Sustainable Smart Cities (BLESS 2020) (in conjunction with ISC2 2020 Conference).
- ♦ The 2nd International Workshop on BLockchain Enabled Sustainable Smart Cities (BLESS 2019) (in conjunction with ISC2 2019 Conference).
- ♦ The 1st International Workshop on Lightweight Blockchain for Edge Intelligence and Security (LightChain 2019).

Reviewer for Journals

- Elsevier Computer Communications
- Elsevier Computer Networks
- Elsevier Computers & Security
- Elsevier Pervasive and Mobile Computing
- ♦ Elsevier Blockchain: Research and Applications
- Elsevier Sustainable Cities and Society
- ♦ Elsevier International Journal of Intelligent Networks
- ♦ IEEE Access
- ♦ IEEE Internet-of-Things Journal (IoT-J)
- ♦ IEEE Transactions on Big Data (TBD)
- ♦ IEEE Transactions on Industrial Informatics (TII)
- ♦ IEEE Transactions on Dependable and Secure Computing (TDSC)
- ♦ IEEE Transactions on Network Science and Engineering (TNSE)
- MDPI Applied Sciences
- MDPI Sensor and Actuator Networks
- Hindawi Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing

Reviewer for Conferences

♦ IEEE International Conference on Computer Communications (INFOCOM)

Professional Services (continued)

- ♦ IEEE International Conference on Blockchain (Blockchain)
- ♦ IEEE Global Communications Conference (GLOBECOM)
- ♦ IEEE International Conference on Wireless and Mobile Computing, Networking And Communications (WiMob)
- ♦ IEEE International Performance Computing and Communications Conference (IPCCC)
- ♦ IEEE International Conference on Consumer Electronics (ICCE)
- ♦ IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC)
- ♦ IEEE International Smart Cities Conference (ISC2)
- ♦ IEEE International Conference on Cloud Networking (CloudNet)
- ♦ ACM Conference on Embedded Networked Sensor Systems (SenSys)
- ♦ EAI SECURECOMM

Miscellaneous Experience

Awards and Achievements

- 2019 **2019 Computers Best Paper Award**, Multidisciplinary Digital Publishing Institute (MDPI).
- outstanding MS Research, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Binghamton University.

On campus Services

 Fall 2018 Leadership Volunteers, International Student and Scholar Services (ISSS), Binghamton University.

Membership

- ♦ IEEE
- ACM